When I was five years old
عندما كان عمري خمس سنوات
I fell in love with airplanes.
وقعت في حب الطائرات
Now I'm talking about the '30s.
اتحدث عن فترة الثلاثينات.
In the '30s an airplane had two wings
في الثلاثينات كان للطائرة جناحان
and a round motor,
ومحرك دائري.
and was always flown
وكان دائما يتم قيادتها
by a guy who looked like Cary Grant.
بواسطة رجل ذو مظهر يشبه الممثل الامريكي كاري جرانت
He had high leather boots,
يرتدي حذاء جلدي طويل,
jodhpurs, an old leather jacket,
بنطال , سترة جلدية قديمة,
a wonderful helmet
خوذة رائعة
and those marvelous goggles --
وتلك النظارات البديعة
and, inevitably, a white scarf,
وحتما وشاح ابيض
to flow in the wind.
ليتطاير مع الرياح
He'd always walk up to his airplane
كان يمشي باتجاه طائرته
in a kind of saunter,
بخطا متئدة
devil-may-care saunter,
خطا متئدة بنوع من الخيلاء
flick the cigarette away,
يلقي بسجارته بعيدا,
grab the girl waiting here, give her a kiss.
يحضن الفتاة التي تنتظره , ويقبلها,
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And then mount his airplane,
ومن ثم يصعد الى طائرته
maybe for the last time.
ربما للمرة الاخيرة
Of course I always wondered what would happen
بالتاكيد لطالما تساءلت ماذا كان سيحدث
if he'd kissed the airplane first.
لوقام بتقبيل الطائرة اولا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But this was real romance to me.
بالنسبة لي كان ذلك حقا شاعري
Everything about flying in those years,
كل ما يخص الطيران في تلك السنين,
which was -- you have to stop and think for a moment --
حيث كان-- علي التوقف والتفكير لبرهة--
was probably the most advanced
كان تقريبا الشيئ
technological thing going on at the time.
التقني الاكثر تقدما في ذلك الوقت
So as a youngster,
وبالتالي كاي شاب
I tried to get close to this
كنت احاول الاقتراب منه
by drawing airplanes,
عن طريق رسم الطائرات
constantly drawing airplanes.
بشكل متواصل ارسم الطائرات.
It's the way I got
انها الوسيلة التي احصل بها
a part of this romance.
على شيء من تلك الشاعرية
And of course, in a way, when I say romance,
وبالطبع .بطريقة ما, عندما اقول شاعرية,
I mean in part
اعني ضمنا
the aesthetics of that whole situation.
حميع الجماليات في ذلك الشيئ
I think the word is the holistic experience
اعتقد ان الكلمة هي التجربة الشاملة
revolving around a product.
تدور حول منتج
The product was that airplane.
المنتج هو الطائرة
But it built a romance.
لكنها شكلت شاعرية
Even the parts of the airplane
حتى اجزاء الطائرة
had French names.
لها اسماء فرنسية
Ze fuselage, ze empanage, ze nessal.
جسم الطائرة, الذيل, nessal*.
You know, from a romance language.
كم تلاحظون, اشتقت من لغة شاعرية
So that it was something that just got into your spirit.
وذلك ماكانت عليه الطائره شيء يتسلل الى روحك
It did mine.
وهو ما حصل لي
And I decided I had to get closer than
وقررت الاقتراب اكثر
just drawing fantasy airplanes.
من مجرد رسم طائرات خيالية
I wanted to build airplanes.
اردت بناء طائرة.
So I built model airplanes.
قمت ببناء نماذج للطائرات
And I found that in doing the model airplanes
ووجدت انه بعمل نماذج للطائرات
the appearance drawings were not enough.
الرسومات لم تكن كفاية
You couldn't transfer those
لا تستطيع تحويلها
to the model itself.
الى نماذج ملموسة
If you wanted it to fly
اذا كنت تريدها ان تطير
you had to learn the discipline
يجب ان تتعلم اساسيات
of flying.
الطيران
You had to learn about aeronautics.
يجب ان تتعلم عن علوم لطيران
You had to learn what made an airplane
يجب ان تتعلم مالذي يجعل الطائرة
stay in the air.
تبقى في الجو.
And of course, as a model in those years, you couldn't control it.
وبالطبع في تلك الايام لا يمكنك التحكم في تلك النماذج.
So it had to be self-righting,
بالتالي كان يجب ان تكون ذاتية التصحيح
and stay up without crashing.
وتحلق عاليا دون ان تتحطم
So I had to give up
بالتالي يجب ان اتوقف
the approach of drawing
عن ذلك الاتجاه في رسم
the fantasy shapes
الاشكال الخيالية,
and convert it to technical drawings --
والتحول باتجاه الرسومات الفنية
the shape of the wing, the shape of the fuselage and so on --
شكل الجناح, شكل جسم الطائرة هكذا.
and build an airplane over these drawings
وبناء طائرة اعتمادا على تلك الرسوم
that I knew followed some of the principles
التي كانت معتمدة على مبادئ
of flying.
الطيران
And in so doing, I could produce
وبعمل ذلك تمكنت من انتاج
a model that would fly, stay in the air.
نموذج بامكانه الطيران ,والبقاء في الجو.
And it had, once it was in the air,
وعندما كانت تحلق كنت اجد فيها
some of this romance that I was in love with.
بعض تلك الشاعرية التي كنت مغرما بها.
Well the act of drawing airplanes
شغفي برسم الطائرات
led me to,
قادني الى,
when I had the opportunity to choose
عندما كان لدي الفرصة لاختيار
a course in school,
تخصصي الدراسي,
led me to sign up for aeronautical engineering.
قادني للتسجيل في هندسة الطيران
And when I was sitting in classes --
وعندما كنت اجلس في الصف
in which no one asked me to draw an airplane --
حيث لم يطلب مني احد رسم طائرة
to my surprise.
تفاجات
I had to learn mathematics and mechanics
بانني علي تعلم الرياضيات والميكانيكا
and all this sort of thing.
وما شابه من تلك المواد
I'd wile away my time drawing airplanes
كنت اقضي وقتي في رسم الطائرات
in the class.
في الصف
One day a young man looked over my shoulder,
وفي احد الايام نظر شاب من خلف كتفي
he said, "You draw very well.
وقال , " انك ترسم بشكل جيد جدا.
You should be in the art department."
يجب ان تكون في كلية الفنون ."
And I said, "Why?"
وقلت ," لماذا ؟"
And he said, "Well for one thing, there are more girls there."
قال , " حسنا لسبب واحد, هو وجود الكثير من الفتيات هناك."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So my romance was temporarily shifted.
فانتقلت شاعريتي بشكل مؤقت .
And I went into art
وذهبت الى الفنون
because they appreciated drawing.
لانهم كانو يقدرون الرسم.
Studied painting; didn't do very well at that.
درست الرسم التشكيلي . لم اكن جيدا في ذلك المجال
Went through design,
تعمقت في التصميم
some architecture.
وشيء من الفن المعماري
Eventually hired myself out as a designer.
وفي نهاية المطاف تقدمت للوظائف كمصمم.
And for the following 25 years,
واستمر ذلك للخمسة وعشرين سنة التالية.
living in Italy,
اعيش في ايطاليا
living in America,
اعيش في امريكا
I doled out a piece of this romance
وفرت شي من هذه الشاعرية
to anybody who'd pay for it --
لاي شخص قادر على دفع ثمنها
this sense, this aesthetic feeling,
هذا الاحساس, وهذه المشاعر الجمالية,
for the experience revolving around
تجاه التجربة التي تدور حول
a designed object.
تصميم شيئ.
And it exists.
ذلك موجودا
Any of you who rode the automobiles --
ايا منكم يركب السيارات--
was it yesterday? --
هل كان ذلك بالامس؟--
at the track, you know the romance
في الطريق , تتعرف على الشاعرية
revolving around those high performance cars.
التي تحيط بتلك السيارات عالية الاداء
Well in 25 years
حسنا خلال 25 سنة
I was mostly putting out
في معظم الاحيان كنت اقتطع
pieces of this romance
اجزاء من تلك الرومانسية
and not getting a lot back in
ولم احصل على الكثير في المقابل
because design on call
لان التصميم حسب الطلب
doesn't always connect you with a circumstance
لا يربطك دائما بالظروف الملائمة
in which you can produce things of this nature.
التي تمكنك من انتاج اشياء بتلك الطبيعة
So after 25 years I began to feel
ولذلك بعد 25 سنة بدأت اشعر
as though I was running dry.
بنوع من الجفاف
And I quit.
وقمت بالاستقالة
And I started up a very small operation --
وبدات بعمل صغير جدا
went from 40 people
بدلا من اربعين موظفا اصبح هناك
to one,
موظفا واحد
in an effort to rediscover my innocence.
في محاولة لاعادة اكتشاف براءتي
I wanted to get back
اردت العودة الى
where the romance was.
حيث توجد الشاعرية
And I couldn't choose airplanes
لم استطع اختيار الطائرات
because they had gotten sort of unromantic
لانها اصبحت بشكل ما تفتقر للشاعرية
at that point,
في تلك اللحظة
even though I'd done a lot of airplane work,
بالرغم من انني انجزت الكثير من الاعمال المتعلقة بالطائرات
on the interiors.
في الجزء الخاص بالتصميم الداخلي.
So I chose furniture.
لذلك اخترت الاثاث..
And I chose chairs specifically
واخترت المقاعد بالتحديد
because I knew something about them.
لانني اعرف شيئا عنها
I'd designed a lot of chairs, over the years
قمت بتصميم الكثير من المقاعد .خلال تلك السنين.
for tractors and trucks
للجرارات والشاحنات
and submarines --
والغواصات
all kinds of things.
جميع الانواع.
But not office chairs.
ما عادا مقاعد المكاتب
So I started doing that.
لذلك بدات بها
And I found that there were ways
واكتشفت ان هناك طرقا
to duplicate the same approach
لتكرير نفس الاسلوب
that I used to use on the airplane.
الذي اعتدت استخدامه في الطائرات.
Only this time,
لكن هذه المرة
instead of the product being shaped by the wind,
بدلا من ان شكل المنتج مرتبطا بالرياح,
it was shaped by the human body.
اصبح يرتبط بجسم الانسان
So the discipline was --
فالقاعدة الاساسية كانت
as in the airplane you learn a lot about
كما في الطائرت كان يجب تعلم الكثير عن
how to deal with the air,
كيفية التعامل مع الهواء
for a chair
بالنسبة للمقعد
you have to learn a lot about how to deal
يجب عليك تعلم الكثير عن كيفية التعامل
with the body,
مع الجسم البشري
and what the body needs, wants,
وما هي احتياجات الجسم ومتطلباته
indicates it needs.
تحديد احتياجاته.
And that's the way, ultimately
ذلك كان المنهج, في نهاية المطاف
after some ups and downs,
بعد بعض النجاحات والاخفاقات,
I ended up designing the chair I'm going to show you.
انتهيت الى تصميم المقعد الذي ساعرضه عليكم.
I should say one more thing. When I was doing those
علي ان اقول شيئا اخر, عندما كنت اصمم
model airplanes,
نماذج الطائرات
I did everything.
قمت بعمل كل شيء
I conceived the kind of airplane.
فهمت طبيعة الطائرة
I basically engineered it.
بشكل اساسي قمت بعمل الشق الهندسي الخاص بها
I built it.
قمت ببنائها
And I flew it.
وجعلتها تطير
And that's the way I work now.
وهو نفس المنهج الذي اتبعه الان
When I started this chair
عندما شرعت في عمل هذا المقعد
it was not a preconceived notion.
لم يكن عبارة عن فكرة مسبقة التصور.
Design nowadays, if you mean it,
التصميم في وقتنا الحالي , اذا كان ذلك ما تعنيه,
you don't start with styling sketches.
لاتبدأه بالرسومات
I started with a lot of loose ideas,
لقد بدأت بالعديد من تلك الافكار الفضفاضة
roughly eight or nine years ago.
تقريبا ثمانية او تسعة سنوات مضت
And the loose ideas had something
وتلك الافكار الفضفاضة احتوت على شيء ما
to do with what I knew happened with
يتعلق بما عرفته عن ما يحصل مع
people in the office,
الناس في المكتب
at the work place -- people who worked,
في مكان العمل, الاشخاص الذين عملوا,
and used task seating,
واستخدموا المقاعد,
a great many of them sitting in front of a computer
قسم عظيم منهم يجلسون مقابل جهاز الحاسب
all day long.
طوال اليوم.
And I felt,
وشعرت,
the one thing they don't need,
ان الشيئ الذي لا يحتاجونه ,
is a chair that interferes
هو مقعد يتعارض
with their main reason for sitting there.
مع السبب الرئيسي لجلوسهم هناك.
So I took the approach
ولذلك اتبعت منهج
that the chair should do as much for them
ان المقعد يجب ان يقدم لهم اقصى قدر
as humanly possible
ممكن يخدمهم كبشر
or as mechanistically possible
وكذالك ميكانيكيا قدر الامكان
so that they didn't have to fuss with it.
بحيث لا يتوجب عليهم القلق كثيرا بشأنه
So my idea was that,
لذلك كانت فكرتي انه
instead of sitting down and reaching
بدلا من الجلوس ومحاولة الوصول
for a lot of controls,
للكثير من ادوات التحكم,
that you would sit on the chair,
فعند جلوسك على المقعد,
and it would automatically balance your weight
سيقوم تلقائيا بموازنة وزنك
against the force required
ضد القوة المطلوبة
to recline.
لتتكئ
Now that may not mean a lot to some of you.
ربما ذلك لا يعني الكثير لبعضكم
But you know most good chairs do recline
لكنكم تعلمون ان معظم المقاعد الجيدة تسمح بالاتكاء
because it's beneficial to open up this joint
لانه من المفيد فتح هذا المفصل
between your legs and your upper body
بين فخذيك والجزء الاعلى من جسمك
for better breathing
لتتنفس بشكل افضل
and better flow.
وتدفق افضل
So that if you sit down
فاذا جلست
on my chair,
على مقعدي,
whether you're five feet tall
لا يفرق ما اذا كان طولك خمسة اقدام,
or six foot six,
او ستة اقدام
it always deals with your weight
سيتعامل دوما مع وزنك
and transfers the amount of force required
ويقوم بنقل القوى المطلوبة
to recline
للاتكاء
in a way that you don't have to look
بطريقة لاتحتاج معها للبحث
for something to adjust.
عن شيء لتضبطوه ليمكنم من عمل ذلك.
I'll tell you right up front,
سوف اخبركم بشكل واضح,
this is a trade off.
هذه مقايضة
There are drawbacks to this.
هناك جوانب سيئة لهذا
One is: you can't
احدها انك لا تستطيع
accommodate everybody.
استيعاب جميع الاشخاص.
There are some very light people,
هناك اشخاص بالغي الخفة.
some extremely heavy people,
واخرون بالغو الثقل
maybe people with a lot of bulk up top.
او اشخاص باجزاء ضخمة في القسم العلوي
They begin to fall off the end of your chart.
سوف يسقطون وفسدون خططك
But the compromise, I felt,
لكن الشيء المرضي انني شعرت
was in my favor
انني قدمت خدمة
because most people don't adjust their chairs.
لان معظم الناس لا يقومون بضبط مقاعدهم.
They will sit in them forever.
سيجلسون عليها للابد
I had somebody on the bus out to the racetrack
كنت مع احادهم في الحافلة في طريقنا للمضمار
tell me about his sister calling him.
واخبرني عن اخته التي تتصل به.
He said she had one of the new, better chairs.
اخبرني انها حصلت على واحد من افضل المقاعد الجديدة
She said, "Oh I love it."
قالت " ياالهي لقد احببته"
She said, "But it's too high."
قالت," لكنه مرتفع جدا"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So he said, "Well I'll come over and look at it."
فقال " حسنا ساحضر والقي نظرة عليه."
He came over and looked at it.
وحضر والقى نظرة عليه
He reached down. He pulled a lever. And the chair sank down.
نظر للاسفل .وقم بسحب مقبض. وانخفض المقعد للاسفل
She said, "Oh it's wonderful. How did you do that?"
قالت, " يالهي ذلك رائع . كيف فعلت ذلك؟"
And he showed her the lever.
واراها المقبض.
Well, that's typical
حسنا. تلك حالة معتادة
of a lot of us working in chairs.
للعديد منا من الذين يعملون في مجال المقاعد.
And why should you
ولماذا يجب عليك
get a 20-page manual
الحصول على كتيب من 20 صفحة
about how to run a chair?
حول كيف تقوم باستعمال مقعد.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I had one for a wristwatch once. 20 pages.
لدي كتيب من عشرين صفحة خاص بساعة اليد.
Anyway, I felt that it was important
علي اي حال, احسست كم كان مهما
that you didn't have to make an adjustment
ان لا يتوجب عليك عمل ضبط
in order to get this kind of action.
للقيام بتلك الحركة
The other thing I felt was that armrests
الامر الاخر شعرت به هو مساند الذراع
had never really been properly approached
لم يتم التعامل معها بشكل مناسب
from the standpoint of how much
من وجهة النظر المتعلقة بالمقدار
of an aid they could be
المقدار الذي يمكن ان تكون به مساعدة
to your work life.
لحياتك العملية
But I felt it was too much to ask
لكنني احسست بالعديد من التساؤلات
to have to adjust each individual armrest
لكي اقوم بضبط كل مسند ذراع على حده
in order to get it where you wanted.
لكي تضعه حيث تريد.
So I spent a long time.
لذلك امضيت وقتا طويلا.
I said I worked eight or nine years on it.
لقد قلت سابقا انني عملت طوال ثمانية او تسعة اعوام عليه
And each of these things went along
وكل تلك الامور
sort of in parallel
مضت في شكل متوازي
but incrementally were a problem of their own.
ولكن بشكل متصاعد كان هناك مشكلة متعلقة بكل منها
I worked a long time on figuring out
امضيت وقتا طويلا للبحث عن حل
how to move the arms over a much greater arc --
لكيفية تحريك الاذرع للاعلى بشكل قوس
that is up and down --
للاعلى والاسفل
and make them a lot easier,
وجعل ذلك بشكل سهل
so that you didn't have to use a button.
بحيث لا تكون مضطرا لاستخدام ازرار
And so after many trials, many failures,
وهكذا الكثير من التجارب والكثير من الاحفاق
we came up with a very simple arrangement
خرجنا بنظام بسيط
in which we could just move
بحيث انه يمكنتا تحريك
one arm or the other.
هذا المسند او الاخر
And they go up easily.
فيرتفعان بسهولة
And stop where you want.
وتوقفهما حيث تريد
You can put them down, essentially out of the way.
ويمكنك انزالهما للاسفل لتبعدهما عن طريقك
No arms at all.
لا مساند على الاطلاق
Or you can pull them up where you want them.
او يمكنك رفعهما الى حيث تريد
And this was another thing that I felt,
وهذا شيئ اخر شعرت به
while not nearly as romantic
ليس بالتاكيد بنفس مقدار الشاعرية
as Cary Grant,
مثل الممثل كاري جرانت,
nevertheless begins to
وبالرغم من ذلك بدات
grab a little bit of aesthetic
اجمع قليل من الجمالية,
operation, aesthetic performance
اداء العملية الجمالية
into a product.
في منتج
The next area that was of interest to me
الجزئية الاخرى التي كانت مهمة بالنسبة لي
was the fact that reclining
هي حقيقة ان الاتكاء للخلف
was a very important factor.
هو عامل مهم جدا
And the more you can recline,
وكلما تمكنت من الاتكاء بشكل اكثر,
in a way, the better it is.
كلما كان ذلك افضل
The more the angle between here and here opens up --
كلم اتسعت الزاوية بين هذا الجزء والاخر,
and nowadays, with a screen in front of you,
وفي وقتتنا الحالي الشاشة تكون امامك,
you don't want to have your eye drop too far in the recline,
بالتالي لاتريد ان تكون مضطرا لخفض عينيك كثير اثناء اتكاءك
so we keep it at more or less the same level --
لذلك حافظنا علي مستواها بقدر االامكان
but you transfer weight
لكنك تنقل الوزن
off your tailbones.
المركز على عظمة المؤخرة
Would everybody put their hand under their bottom
هلا قام الجميع بوضع اياديهم اسفل منهم
and feel their tailbone?
وتحسس عظمة المؤخرة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You feel that bone under there?
هل تشعر بتلك العظمة؟
Just your own.
فقط عظمتك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There's two of them, one on either side.
هناك عظمتان .واحدة في كل جانب.
All the weight of your upper torso --
كامل الوزن الخاص بجذعك الاعلى,
your arms, your head --
ذراعاك وراسك,
goes right down through your back,
يذهب للاسفل من خلال ظهرك
your spine, into those bones when you sit.
وعامودك الفقري,الى تلك العظمتين اثناء جلوسك
And that's a lot of load.
وذلك حمل كبير
Just relieving your arms with armrests
باراحتك لذراعيك على مسند الاذرعة
takes 20 percent of that load off.
تزيل نسبة 20 % من ذلك الحمل
Now that, if your spine is not held in a good position,
الان ,اذا كان عمودك الفقري ليس في وضعه الصحيح,
will help bend your spine the wrong way, and so on.
ذلك سيساعد في انحناءه بطريقة خاطئة,وهكذا.
So to unload
ولازالة الحمل
that great weight --
حمل وزنك الثقيل
if that indeed exists --
اذا كان موجودا ,
you can recline.
يمكنك الاسترخاء للخلف
When you recline you take away a lot of that load
عندما تتكئ للخلف تزيل الكثير من الحمل
off your bottom end, and transfer it to your back.
عن مؤخرتك ,وتحوله الى ظهرك
At the same time, as I say, you open up this joint.
في نفس الوقت,كما اسلفت ,تفتح هذا المفصل.
And breathability is good.
ويصبح التنفس افضل
But to do that, if you have any
لكن عند القيام بأي
amount of recline,
قدر من الاتكاء للخلف
it gets to the point where you need a headrest
تصل لمرحلة تحتاج فيها لمسند للرأس
because nearly always,
لانه دائما
automatically hold your head
يحمل رأسك تلقائيا
in a vertical position, see?
في وضع عامودي,انظر؟
As I recline, my head says more or less vertical.
عندما اتكئ للخلف ,يظل راسي بصورة عامودية
Well if you're reclined a great deal,
واذا اتكأت للخلف
you have to use muscle force
يتوجب عليك استخدام قواك العضلية
to hold your head there.
لابقاء راسك في الوضع المطلوب
So that's where a headrest comes in.
وهنا يأتي دور مساند الرأس
Now headrest is a challenge
مساند الرأس بحد ذاتها هي تحدي
because you want it to adjust
لانك تريدها ان تضبط
enough so that it'll fit,
بشكل كاف لتلائم
you know, a tall guy and a short girl.
مختلف الاجسام ,رجل طويل, فتاة قصيرة
So here we are.
وهنا نصل للنقطة المهمة
I've got five inches of adjustment here
وضعت خمسة انشات من قابلية الضبط هنا
in order to get the headrest in the right place.
للاتمكن من وضع الرأس في المكان الصحيح
But then I knew from experience
ولكنني بحكم التجربة
and looking around in offices
والتجول في المكاتب
where there were chairs with headrests
حيث يوجد مقاعد بمساند رأس
that nobody would ever bother
لم يكلف اي شخص نفسه عناء
to reach back and turn a knob
الوصول بيده للخلف وادارة المقبض
and adjust the headrest to put it in position.
وضبط مسند الرأس في موضعه
And you need it in a different position
وتريده في موضع مختلف
when you're upright, then when you're reclined.
حين تكون منتصبا, وحين تكون متكئا للخلف
So I knew that had to be solved, and had to be automatic.
لذك علمت انه يحب ان تحل هذه المعضلة وبشكل تلقائي
So if you watch this chair
فعندما تنظر إلى هذا المقعد
as I recline, the headrest comes up
عندما اتكئ للخلف , يصعد مسند الرأس
to meet my neck.
ليقابل رقبتي
Ideally you want to put the head support
في المكان الملائم لدعم رأسك
in the cranial area, right there.
في هذه المنطقة الحساسة
So that part of it took a long time
ولذلك فان هذا الجزء من المقعد استغرق وقتا طويلا
to work out.
لانجازه
And there is a variety of other things: the shape of the cushions,
وهناك اشياء اخرى مختلفة, شكل الوسائد
the gel we put.
المادة الهلامية التي وضعناها
We stole the idea from bicycle seats,
سرقنا الفكرة من مقاعد الدراجات
and put gel in the cushions
ووضعنا مادة هلامية في المساند
and in the armrests
وفي مساند الاذرع
to absorb point load --
لتمتص الثقل--
distributes the loading so you don't get hard spots.
ولتوزيع الحمل بحيث لا يكون هناك اماكن دائمة التعرض للثقل
You cant hit your elbow
لا يمكنك ضرب مرفقك
on bottom.
في الاسفل
And I did want to demonstrate
وكنت ارغب بتوضيح
the fact that the chair can accommodate people.
حقيقة ان هذا المقعد يمكنه استيعاب الاشخاص
While you're sitting in it you can adjust it
بينما تكون جالسا عليه يمكنك ضبطه
down for the five-footer,
للاسفل ليناسب من طولهم خمسة اقدام
or you can adjust it
او يمكنك ضبطه
for the six-foot-six guy --
ليلائم من طولهم ستة اقدام
all within the scope of a few simple adjustments.
كل ذلك في نطاق قليل من الضبط البسيط
(Applause)
(تصفيق)